Friday, four-fifty PM. A merge request lands —
"add the production env file."
The reviewer's tired, with eight more in the queue.
Inside this diff: a database password, a JWT secret,
a live Stripe key, an AWS access key —
everything policy says must never hit the repo.
This is how secrets ship.
MR Sentinel is the reviewer that never gets tired.
The moment an MR opens, MR Sentinel — a Google Agent
Development Kit agent on Cloud Run — wakes up.
Watch it actually run.
Read the log — this is the agent running.
"ADK evaluate, via GitLab MCP": it spins up
GitLab's own MCP server and calls it directly —
get-merge-request, get-merge-request-diffs,
list-pipelines, each one going through MCP.
It hands all that to Gemini, on Vertex AI, which
judges the diff against fifteen rules at once
and records a structured verdict. Every MCP call
logged and replayable — about thirty seconds end to end.
And here's what it leaves on the merge request
that started this.
Verdict: block. Score: zero out of ten.
It cites no-secrets-in-diff by rule ID — mapped to
SOC 2, ISO 27001, OWASP — and quotes the exact lines,
opens a remediation issue with a checklist,
and labels it blocked-compliance.
Every action ties back to a named control.
That's one MR. Here's the portfolio — the last
thirty days, every MR scored,
most blocked on compliance, the top failing rules,
each one a control mapped to an audit framework.
Click any one and you're in the audit log —
every outcome, every control mapping, the timeline.
At year-end, that's just… there.
Three deliberate choices. GitLab's MCP server for
the reads — a portable tool surface:
the same agent points at gitlab.com or a
self-hosted instance with no rewiring.
ADK, because governance needs a real tool-calling
loop and a structured verdict, not a chat reply.
And Gemini on Vertex, so no diff
ever leaves Google Cloud.
One honest seam: reads run through MCP, write-backs
use GitLab's REST API — the Duo server can't post yet.
Every regulated engineering org has this exact
pain — and most ship the secret anyway.
One ADK agent, Gemini for the judgment,
GitLab's MCP server for reach,
and one rubric where every rule is a named compliance
control. It ships MIT — fork it, run your own.
The audit trail is just the byproduct. MR Sentinel.